A Guide to the Round Hill Woman's Club Records, 1946-2006
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Round Hill Woman's Club Records, 1946-2006
Thomas Balch Library
M 099, VC 0063
.5 cubic feet, 1 scrapbook, 295 photographs.
There is one box of folders of minutes and supporting documentation, one oversized box containing the scrapbook, and one box of photographs.
Ann Whitehead Thomas, Winchester, VA
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Ann Whitehead Thomas, Winchester, VA
Alternative Form Available
None
Accruals
2006.0175
Historical Information
Organized on 8 July 1946, the Round Hill Woman's Club consisted of twelve charter members dedicated to improving themselves and their community. They were especially interested in promoting the education, safety, and welfare of children in Round Hill. They joined the Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs in 1947. The club decided to leave the federation in 1973, however, feeling that the larger organization no longer provided the resources that the women of Round Hill wanted.
The Round Hill Woman's Club held monthly meetings for the members to gather, listen to a host's program, and discuss what they could do to better their community. In the 1940s to the 1960s, the club supported many projects within the community such as a clothes closet for the Round Hill School, hosting an annual reception for Round Hill school teachers, and sending money to the Loudoun County Guidance Center and Round Hill Fire Department. They held fundraisers such as card parties, fashion shows, and donation suppers to collect money for their causes. Since they were especially concerned with music, art, and religious training for children, they provided funding for a music and art teacher for Round Hill Elementary School for several years.
During the 1970s, the Round Hill Woman's Club stopped hosting fundraisers and instead, increased membership fees to continue supporting community organizations. As the years progressed, their community involvement decreased, and the club became concerned largely with improvement of the members. To improve themselves personally, the host of the monthly meeting would prepare a program or invite a speaker to inform the women about everything from flower arranging to the juvenile delinquency. Additionally, the club hosted yearly luncheons and trips to local areas of interest.
As of 2014, the Round Hill Woman's Club was still in existence.
Scope and Content
There is one box of folders, one oversized box containing the scrapbook, and one box of photographs.
The records consist of monthly meeting minutes written by the club secretary for the year, an attendance and membership list for each year, yearly summaries of the club's activities compiled by the secretary through the 1960s, and yearbooks issued annually to the members of the club containing a schedule of events and the addresses and phone numbers of each member. Additionally, the club kept records of their contributions to other organizations, and newspaper articles containing information about the members of the club.
The scrapbook, started in 1946 and ending around 2004, contains newspaper clippings of club activities, obituaries of club members, yearbooks, and letters received by the Round Hill Woman's Club.
The photographs document meetings, trips, and activities hosted by the Round Hill Woman's Club from 1988-2006.
Arrangement
Box: folder
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Round Hill Woman's Club Records (M 099), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Other Finding Aid
None
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
Round Hill Woman's Club Collection (SC 0068), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Contents List
    - Member Attendance Records 1946-1992, 1998-1999, 2002-2004
    - Minutes, 1946-1951
    - Minutes, 1952-1957
    - Minutes, 1958-1963
    - Minutes, 1964-1969
    - Minutes, 1970-1975
    - Minutes, 1976-1981
    - Minutes, 1982-1987
    - Minutes, 1988-1992
    - Minutes, 2001-2004
    - Birth and Death Notices
    - Constitution and By-Laws
    - Correspondence
    - Histories, 1961-1996
    - Loudoun County Guidance Center
    - Newspaper clippings
    - Presidential Tips
    - "Promoter of Unsung Heroes" by Ann Harrington
    - Report on Activities for Youth, 1966
    - Round Hill School Awards Ceremony, 1992
    - Virginia Federation of Women's Clubs
    - Yearbooks, 1970-1979
    - Yearbooks, 1984-2004
    - Year Summaries, 1946-1959, 1965-1969
    - Four oversized photos from VC 0063
    - Round Hill Woman's Club scrapbook, 1946-2004
    - [Sky Meadows, June 1990]
    - [Luncheon at Hamilton Garden Inn, 1991]
    - [Lunch with Barbara Mayns at North Cliff, Rixeyville, Culpepper Co, VA, September 1991]
    - [Lunch with Barbara Mayns at North Cliff, September 1992]
    - [Christmas Luncheon, Loudoun Golf and Country Club, Purcellville, 1990]
    - [Picnic at Edna Krantz's]
    - [Luncheon, Winchester, April 1996]
    - [Meeting at Ann Harrington's, 1989]
    - [Meeting at Jean Demyttenaere's, 1995]
    - [Luncheon, Battletown Inn, Berryville, 1988]
    - [Luncheon, July 1994]
    - [Picnic at Edna Krantz's, 1990]
    - [Luncheon, Loudoun Golf and Country Club, April 1995]
    - [Picnic at the Lauterborne's, 1988]
    - [Trip, 1985]
    - [Trip]
    - [Couple with donated goods]
    - [Awards for Round Hill School, 1992]
    - [Christmas Lunch, Carrodec Hall, Leesburg, 1996]
    - [Meeting at Charlotte Goodsen's, 1999]
    - [Meeting at Bennie Lightner's, 1999]
    - [Meeting at Jean Demyttenaere's, 2000]
    - [Special Luncheon at Mac Brownell's, 2000]
    - [Picnic at Edna Krantz's, 2001]
    - [Jane Carlson's Anne Edwards AAA program, 2000]
    - [Marion Sweet's Mystery Theatre, 2001]
    - [60th Anniversary Luncheon, Loudoun Golf and Country Club, July 2006]
    - [Mary Elizabeth Paulson Myers, Westminster Canterbury, Winchester, "Mother of John and Charles Wesley" program, March 2004]
    - [60th Anniversary Luncheon, Loudoun Golf and Country Club, Purcellville VA, July 2006]
    - [From "Report on Activities for Youth," M 009, Box 1 Folder 19]
    - [Round Hill Woman's Club 60th Anniversary, July 2006]
    - [Christmas, Loudoun Golf and Country Club, 2002]
    - [Round Hill Woman's Club picnic at the Lauterborne's, 1988]
    - [Christmas Luncheon, 1990]
    - [Lunch with Barbara Mayns, Rixeyville, Culpepper Co, VA; Visit to North Cliff, September 1991]
    - [Meeting with Barbara Mayns, September 1992]
    - No title, [1994]
    - No title, 1992
    - [Date and location unknown]
    - [Lunch, Beautiful South Hamilton (oversized, in M 099 Folder 25)]